A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Papers, 1860s-1960s
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
James Branch Cabell Papers, 1860s-1960s
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 214
10 linear feet and 3000 volume library
James Branch Cabell
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated to the Special Collections and Archives Department by Margaret Freeman Cabell in 1976.
Biographical/Historical Information
Richmond author James Branch Cabell (1879-1958) is best known for his controversial Jurgen (1919), one of several ironic fantasies he wrote that took place in Cabell's mythical medieval world of Poictesme (Pwa- tem). Jurgen, laced with erotic overtones, was considered pornographic by some and a trial over its content brought the reclusive writer national fame. Throughout the 1920s, Cabell was highly regarded by his literary peers -- H.L. Mencken, Sinclair Lewis, and others praised his works. His medieval romanticism and fantasy were in fact thinly disguised commentary on the manners of those times.
Cabell was born April 14, 1879 at 101 E. Franklin St., the present site of the Richmond Public Library. His father was Robert Gamble Cabell, II (1847-1922), a physician; his mother Anne Harris (1859-1915), daughter of Col. and Mrs James R. Branch. Cabell's great grandfather was William H. Cabell, governor of Virginia from 1805-1808. Cabell had two brothers, Robert Gamble Cabell, III (1881-1968) and John Lottier Cabell (1883-1946). His parents separated and were later divorced in 1907.
After attending William and Mary College (1893-1898), where he taught courses in French and Greek while an undergraduate, Cabell worked briefly at the Richmond Times as a copy-holder. Beginning in 1899 he lived for two years in New York City, working for the New York Herald as a social reporter, serving for a time in the paper's Harlem office. In 1901 he returned to Richmond and worked several months on the staff of the Richmond News. During the next ten years he performed genealogical research and wrote many short stories and articles, contributing to national magazines such as Harper's Monthly Magazine and the Saturday Evening Post.
In 1911, he was employed as a bookkeeper in the office of his uncle's (James R. Branch) coal mine in West Virginia. He returned to Richmond in 1913 and married Rebecca Priscilla Bradley Shepherd (1874-1949), a widow with five children by her previous marriage. They had one son, Ballard Hartwell Cabell (1915-1980).
Although he had written for newspapers, Cabell's first work to be published in a journal was a college paper entitled The Comedies of William Congreve which appeared in the April 1901 edition of International. His first book, The Eagle's Shadow, was published in the autumn of 1904 after it appeared serially in the Saturday Evening Post during that summer. Whether it was his highly mannered prose or the fact that he was writing ironic romances, his work was slow to draw critical attention. By 1918 he had published 10 major works and began to attract critical admirers. In an article published that year in the New York Evening Mail, H.L. Mencken described Cabell as "the only first-rate literary craftsman that the whole South can show." Cabell's stature and fame as an author grew immensely with the 1919 publication of Jurgen.
On January 14, 1920, the New York State Society for the Prevention of Vice charged Cabell's publishing editor, Guy Holt, with violation of the anti-obscenity provisions of the New York State Penal Code by publishing Jurgen. The controversy over the charges and the attempt at censorship brought the shy Cabell much notoriety. Writers defended the artistry of Jurgen and Cabell's right to publish it. College students and others read it because it had been banned.
The obscenity trial over Jurgen began October 16, 1922, and ended three days later with an acquittal of all charges. Judge Charles C. Nott, the presiding judge, wrote in his decision that "...the most that can be said against the book is that certain passages therein may be considered suggestive in a veiled and subtle way of immorality, but such suggestions are delicately conveyed" and that because of Cabell's writing style "...it is doubtful if the book could be read or understood at all by more than a very limited number of readers."
Throughout the 1920s, he continued to publish in the style of Jurgen, a combination of satire, symbolism and fantasy, set in a mythical medieval French provence, called Poictesme (Pwa-tam). The name was a compound of two provinces located in the south of France, Poitiers and Angouleme. In these books, Cabell blended an assortment of myths and legends laced with puns, anagrams, and allegories. These works eventually became part of an eighteen-volume collection entitled The Biography of the Life of Manuel. The last volume was published in 1930.
Cabell had become well regarded by prominent writers of the period and maintained an extensive correspondence with a wide circle of literary artists and friends, including Mencken, Joseph Hergesheimer, Burton Rascoe, Theodore Dreiser, Sinclair Lewis, F. Scott Fitzgerald, Carl Van Vechten, and fellow Richmonder and close friend Ellen Glasgow. He had known Glasgow since his days at William and Mary College. He also served as editor of the Virginia War History Commission (1919-1926) and later joined Dreiser, Eugene O'Neil and others on the editorial board of the American Spectator (1932-1935). In 1937, Cabell was elected to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
While the controversy over Jurgen insured Cabell an audience throughout most of the 1920s, interest in his books dropped sharply in the New Deal era of the 1930s and continued to decline. His work was considered outdated, his writing too stylized.
In 1932, in an attempt to break away from his past, he began to publish work under the name Branch Cabell. During the next three decades he wrote and published nearly twenty more books. They were grouped in a series of trilogies. He returned as James Branch Cabell in 1947 with the publication of Let Me Lie. It was the first installment of his fifth and last trilogy, consisting largely of semi-autobiographical essays, filled with remembrances of Virginia.
Cabell continued to live and work in Richmond, residing at 3201 Monument Avenue. He and his family began to spend most of their winter months in St. Augustine, Florida after Cabell began to suffer from attacks of pneumonia in 1935. During their stay in Florida in 1949, his wife died of heart failure. In 1950, he married Margaret Waller Freeman (1893?-1983), whom he had known for many years. Cabell suffered a cerebral hemorrhage in 1958 and on May 5, he died at his home in Richmond.
Cabell's writings, published in various magazines, newspapers and anthologies, included numerous short stories, poetry, essays, book reviews and one play. He had authored more than 52 volumes of work, including three devoted to genealogy.
Cabell is recognized as one of the first contemporary writers from the South. Like his friend and fellow Richmond writer Ellen Glasgow (1873-1945), Cabell was not afraid to satirize what he saw as the South's contradictions. Others, noting Cabell's unique blending of classic myths and legends with his own imagination, consider him a pioneer of fantasy writing. His work has been admired by a diverse group of writers, including Carl Van Vechten, Margaret Mitchell, Edmund Wilson, Robert Heinlein, and Neil Gaiman.
Soon after Virginia Commonwealth University was established in 1968, when the Medical College of Virginia merged with Richmond Professional Institute, the University began plans for a new library for the Academic Campus. In 1970, the James Branch Cabell Library, named for one of Richmond's most respected writers, opened its doors.
Scope and Content Information
The collection is composed of a great deal of material that had been placed by Cabell in books that made up his personal library which numbered about 3,000 volumes and was donated to the library in the 1970s.
The collection includes correspondence with a number of noted American and British writers of the 20th century including H.L. Mencken, Ellen Glasgow, Sinclair Lewis, and Theodore Dreiser. There is also correspondence with family, friends, editors and publishers.
The collection also contains manuscripts of Cabell's work dating primarily from 1900 through 1930. Published reviews and criticisms of Cabell's work by various editors and writers is also included. The papers also contain a large collection of periodicals where Cabell's essays, reviews and fiction were published. Published and unpublished dramatic and musical interpretations of Cabell's work by others is included in the collection. Newspaper clippings, photographs, periodicals, criticisms, printed material, and publishers' agreements and statements of sales are also found in the collection. The collection also contains notebooks and scrapbooks compiled by Cabell documenting his early years as a writer.
The papers dating from 1963-1971 of the Cabell Society and correspondence between its founders is included in the collection as well as materials concerning Between Friends: Letters of James Branch Cabell and Others which was published in 1962.
Much of the material in Series I, II, III and VIII was taken from the nearly 3,000 volumes in Cabell's personal library. Cabell placed letters, newspaper clippings, photographs, illustrations, typed and written revisions of his works and other memorabilia in his books. In 1967, Cabell's library was cataloged by then doctoral student Jean Maurice Duke. He assigned each volume a "Duke" number and gave a description of each book and its contents. Prof. Duke would later serve as a long time faculty member of VCU's English Department.
In the 1970s his library (some 3,000 volumes) was moved from his home on Monument Avenue to VCU's James Branch Cabell Library. A sizable portion of that material was laminated at the Barrow lab at the Virginia State Library, paid for by Margaret Freeman Cabell.
Items taken from Cabell's library will have a Duke number written in pencil on it, indicating what volume the material was taken from. See James Branch Cabell's Library: A Catalogue by Jean Maurice Duke to determine from which book the item came.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically.
Organization
Series I--Correspondence (1860s-1960s)
Series II--Manuscripts
Series III--Ephemera, printed material, illustrations, newspaper clippings, etc.
Series IV--Cabell Society (1963- 1971)
Series V-- Between Friends
Series VI--Criticisms of Cabell's work
Series VII--Periodicals (essays, reviews and fiction by Cabell)
Series VIII--Dramatic and musical interpretations of Cabell's work
Series IX- -Scrapbooks, notebooks and oversized items
Contents List
- Series I--Correspondence 1860s-1960s
  - Adler, Elmer 1929-1936 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Anderson, Sherwood 1922-1942 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Alden, H.M. 1906-1910 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Althouse, James A.W. 1920 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Amateis, Edmond 1924-1925 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Abramson, Ben 1930 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Abramson, Ben 1930 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Beer, Thomas 1922-1931 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Benet, Stephen Vincent 1939-1943 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Bernhard, William J. (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Bjorkman, Edwin 1921-1931 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Bacheller, Irving 1940 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Balch, Emily Clark 1927 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Baldwin, Charles C. 1919 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Ballou, Robert O. 1936 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Barnhard, Ruth Loomis 1931 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Baskin, Norton 1956 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Bassett, Mrs. John S. 1949 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Bates, Ernest S. 1927 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Baugh, Hansell 1921 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Becker, May Lamberton 1947 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Benet, William Rose 1920, 1942 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Bierstadt, Edward Hale 1920 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Bishop, John Peale 1922 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Blackstone, Florence 1925 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Bley, Franz 1922 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Bochroch, Albert R. 1933 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Boni, Albert 1925 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Boni and Liverright 1928 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Boyd, Ernest, n.d. 1921, 1932 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Boynoton, Percy H. 1924 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Bradley, D. (McBride Co.) 1932 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Branch, Anna Hempstead 1929 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Bregenzer, Helen M. 1931 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Brett, George P., Jr. 1936 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Brewster, Paul C. 1942 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Bruce, Philip A. 1915-1922 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Brussell, I.R. 1927 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Buck, Mitchell S. 1922-1946 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Burgess, Gelett 1922 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Burleigh, Louise 1926 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Burnett, Whit 1937-1946 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Burt, Katherine N., n.d. (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Byrne, Donn 1921 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Copies and Originals of letter sent by Cabell (Box-folder 1.9)
  - Cabell, Margaret 1950s (Box-folder 1.10)
  - Cabell Family Correspondence 1860s-1870s (Box-folder 1.11)
  - Crowley, Aleister 1920-1942 (Box-folder 1.12)
  - Canby, Henry S. 1920-1933 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Cerf, Bennett A. 1932 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons 1912 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Chidsey, Donald B. 1923-1928 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Child, Charles 1938-1940 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Chubb, Thomas C. 1923-1930 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Clark, Alice, n.d. (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Clark, Barrett H. 1921 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Cleaton, Allen 1930 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Coleman, Mary Haldane 1948 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Collins, Joseph 1925 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Collins, Seward 1930 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Coman, Morris 1926 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Conklin, Goff 1929 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Cooper, A. Page (Dblday) 1927, 1934 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Corley, Donald 1927, 1930 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Cosgrave, John O'Hara II 1946 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Cover, James P. 1928 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Coyle, Ray 1923 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Cranwell, John P. 1932 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Croft-Cooke, Rupert 1927, 1929 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Culver, Henry B. 1945, 1946 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Cutting, Mary Steward 1922 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Dreiser, Theodore 1928-1937 (Box-folder 1.14)
  - Dallet, Morris 1922, 1923 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - Daniel, Frank 1946 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - Davis, Elmer 1928 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - DeCassares, Benjamin 1920-1945 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - DeLuca, Angelo 1927 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - Drinkwater, John 1931 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - Dunham, David R. 1941 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - Empty envelopes addressed to JBC (Box-folder 1.16)
  - Eddison, E.R. 1935 (Box-folder 1.17)
  - Eddy, Frederick B. 1927 (Box-folder 1.17)
  - Emmons, Earl H. 1938 (Box-folder 1.17)
  - Evans, Montgomery 1949 (Box-folder 1.17)
  - Farrar, John 1927-1946 (Box-folder 1.18)
  - Fadiman, Clifton P. 1930 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Ferrier, Gladys 1929 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Fischer, John 1947 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Fisk, Earl E. 1932 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Follett, Wilson 1918-1920, 1960 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Forman, Justin Miles 1902-1905 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Freeman, D.S. 1932 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Fuller, H.B. 1920 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Glasgow, Ellen 1923-1945 (Box-folder 1.20)
  - Letters (Box-folder 1.21)
    Letters from six different governors of six different states each thanking JBC for autographing a copy of one of his books. Pinchot, Gov. Gifford (Pennsylvania); Pollard, Gov. Jno Garland (Va.); Ritchie, Gov. Albert C. (Maryland); Seligman, Gov. Arthur (New Mexico); Wilson, Gov. Stanley C. (Vermont).
  - Gallagher, Marie 1932-1935 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Garnett, David 1923 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Geffen, Felicia 1942 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Gekle, William F., Jr. 1950, 1957 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Giroux, Robert 1946 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Glenn, Garrard 1922-1932 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Goldsmith, Alfred, n.d. (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Goudy, Frederick W. 1938 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Greenslet, Ferris 1928 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Hellman, George S. 1924-1931 (Box-folder 2.23)
  - Hergesheimer, Joseph 1920-1930 (Box-folder 2.24)
  - Hotlt, Guy 1917-1929 (Box-folder 2.25)
  - Horan, Tom, n.d. 1930-1931, 1949, 1966 (Box-folder 2.26)
  - Haardt, Sara, n.d. 1920s (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Hallock, R.F. 1942 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Hambidge 1920 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Hamilton, Kay (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Hanna, Fred 1946 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Harper and Brothers 1904, 1912 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Hartwick, Harry 1934 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Haverlin, Carl 1955 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Hawkins, Arthur Jr. 1934 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Helm, Florence, n.d. (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Henderson, Archibald 1922 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Hervey, Harry 1941 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Hewlett, Maurice 1919 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Heyward, DuBose 1932 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Himler, Mary Rose 1929 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Hobson, Thayer 1928 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Holliday, Robert C. 1919 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Holt, Rackam 1935, 1947 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Horton, Mary Beatty 1920s (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Houdini, Beatrice, n.d. (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Howells, W.D. 1909 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Huneker, James 1916 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - H.E. Janee, n.d. (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Irwin, William Wallace 1947 (Box-folder 2.28)
  - Johnson, Merle 1920-1921 (Box-folder 2.29)
  - Jester, David Jr. 1924 (Box-folder 2.30)
  - John Lane Company 1916 (Box-folder 2.30)
  - Johnson, A. 1945 (Box-folder 2.30)
  - Johnson, James Sydney 1927 (Box-folder 2.30)
  - Johnston, Mary 1919 (Box-folder 2.30)
  - Karsner, David 1927 (Box-folder 2.31)
  - Keating, George T. 1929-1933 (Box-folder 2.32)
  - Kipling, Rudyard 1919 (Box-folder 2.33)
  - Kelson, J.D. 1922 (Box-folder 2.34)
  - Kelpner, A.H. 1949 (Box-folder 2.34)
  - Kenan, William R., Jr. 1946 (Box-folder 2.34)
  - Klinefelter, Walter 1928-1936 (Box-folder 2.34)
  - Lewis, Sinclair 1920 (Box-folder 2.35)
  - Lambright, E.D. 1946 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - LaMonte, John L. 1927 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Lange, W.W. 1926 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Lanier, Henry W. 1904, 1908 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Laverack, Belle R. 1919, 1934 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Lawson, Katherine S. 1940 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Lee, Doris 1943 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Lerew, Laurie Mrs. 1960 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Lever, H. Randolph 1922 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Lewis, Grace Hegger 1931 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Lewis, Gracie 1956 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Licht, Michael 1927 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Lilly, Josiah K. Jr. 1944 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Linscott, R.N. 1919 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Littell Robert 1922 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Liveright, Horace D. 1926 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Liveright, Horace (Pub.) 1928 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Locher, Robert E. 1928 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Loverman, Samuel 1927 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - L'Engle, William 1946 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Macy, John 1919-1932 (Box-folder 2.37)
  - McCarthy, Catherine 1960 (Box-folder 2.38)
  - Mencken, H.L. 1919-1946 (Box-folder 2.39)
  - MacGill, Patricia 1947 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Machen, Arthur 1918-1919 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Macrae, John Jr. 1935, 1940 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Malcomson, David 1941 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Mann, W.D. 1904 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Mason, Harold T. 1932 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - McBride, Robert M. 1927-1942 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - McCormick, Elsie 1929 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - McKaughan, J.A. 1934 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - McNeill, Warren A. 1925-1931, 1947 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Meade, Julian R. 1932, 1937 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Mitchell, David M. 1926-1927 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Morrissette, Bruce Archer, n.d. (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Morse, Willard S. 1928 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Mukerji, Dhan G. 1923, 1930 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Mullins, Helene, n.d. (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Nathan, George Jean 1921-1934 (Box-folder 2.41)
  - Nathan, Robert 1921-1946 (Box-folder 2.42)
  - Newman, Frances 1920-1928 (Box-folder 2.43)
  - Norman, Charles 1929-1939 (Box-folder 2.44)
  - Newman, Henry A. 1928 (Box-folder 2.45)
  - Nichols, Robert M. B. 1923-1928 (Box-folder 2.45)
  - Niles, Edward A. 1925 (Box-folder 2.45)
  - O'Neill, Eugene 1934 (Box-folder 2.46)
  - Obernodorfer, H.W. 1940 (Box-folder 2.47)
  - Orcutt, William Dana 1927-1929 (Box-folder 2.47)
  - Overton, Grant 1925 (Box-folder 2.47)
  - O'Neil, Mary Coyle 1942 (Box-folder 2.47)
  - Pape, Frank 1921-1935 (Box-folder 2.48)
  - Posselt, Erich 1928-1929 (Box-folder 2.49)
  - Page, Walter H. 1904 (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Parsons, Charles 1924 (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Paterson, Isabel 1930s (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Patterson, Margaret N. 1928 (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Patton, J.G. (postcard) 1912 (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Payne, L.W., Jr. 1925 (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Peterkin, Julia M., n.d. (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Pollak, Valentin 1931 (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Powell, Louise, Mrs John 1932 (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Pruette, Lorine 1930 (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Pyle, Howard 1906 (Box-folder 2.50)
  - Rascoe, Burton 1918, 1920 (Box-folder 3.51)
  - Rawlings, Margaret K 1942-1953 (Box-folder 3.52)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore 1905 (Box-folder 3.53)
  - Redman, Ben Ray 1922, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 3.54)
  - Remenyi, Joseph 1935 (Box-folder 3.54)
  - Reniers, Perceval 1941 (Box-folder 3.54)
  - Ridgely, Charles 1927 (Box-folder 3.54)
  - Robertson, P.W. 1922 (Box-folder 3.54)
  - Robinson, James H. 1923-1924 (Box-folder 3.54)
  - Rosenberger, Francis C. 1947 (Box-folder 3.54)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul 1926 (Box-folder 3.54)
  - Rouse, Blair 1960 (Box-folder 3.54)
  - Stagg, Hunter 1920s-1940s (Box-folder 3.55)
  - Starrett, Vincent 1920-1928, 1940, 1960 (Box-folder 3.56)
  - Sterling, George 1920-1930 (Box-folder 3.57)
  - Salisbury, William 1929 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Sandfort, J.A. 1929 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Saunders, Margaret V. 1921 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Schaeffer, Samuel B. 1932-1933 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Schaeffer, Samuel B. 1933 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Seymour, George Steele 1920-1921 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Shanks, Lewis P. 1921 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Shawn, Ted 1928 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Sheed, Frank 1947 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Sherer, Adelaide R. 1942 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Shipley, Joseph T., n.d. (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Smith, Douglas 1926 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Smith, T.R. 1920-1927 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Spingarn, J.E. 1924 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Stevenson, Burton 1925 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Stevenson, Burton E. 1923-1924 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Steward, Sam M. 1928-1930 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Stewart, Donald O. 1921 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Street, Julian Jr. 1944-1945 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Sutliff, Milo J. 1932 (Box-folder 3.58)
  - Taylor, Deems 1921-1925 (Box-folder 3.59)
  - Taylor, Walter F. 1956 (Box-folder 3.60)
  - Thompson, Dorothy 1949 (Box-folder 3.60)
  - Tietjens, Sybil Miss 1927 (Box-folder 3.60)
  - Tompkins, Ellen 1913 (Box-folder 3.60)
  - Trotti, Lamar 1928 (Box-folder 3.60)
  - Troubetzkoy, Amelie 1920-1921 (Box-folder 3.60)
  - Tutwiler, Carrington C. 1960 (Box-folder 3.60)
  - Underwood, Leon 1920-1926 (Box-folder 3.61)
  - Unsigned Letter, New York City address, n.d. (Box-folder 3.62)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, n.d. 1920-1923 (Box-folder 3.63)
  - Van Doren, Carl 1908, 1921-1942 (Box-folder 3.64)
  - Van Vechten, Carl 1926-1932 (Box-folder 3.65)
  - Viereck, George S. 1920-1932 (Box-folder 3.66)
  - Van Doren, Mark 1925 (Box-folder 3.67)
  - Van Nortwick, Virginia 1938 (Box-folder 3.67)
  - Verlaine, Dee 1930 (Box-folder 3.67)
  - Wharton, Edith 1920 (Box-folder 3.68)
  - Wilson, Edmund 1922, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 3.69)
  - Wall, Bernhardt 1926 (Box-folder 3.70)
  - Walpole, Hugh, n.d. 1920-1923 (Box-folder 3.70)
  - Walsh, Richard J. 1926 (Box-folder 3.70)
  - Ward, Harold 1922-1923 (Box-folder 3.70)
  - Waterhouse, Francis A. 1940 (Box-folder 3.70)
  - Webb, Mrs. J.A. 1919 (Box-folder 3.70)
  - Weil, Maurice K. 1929 (Box-folder 3.70)
  - Wells, James R. 1938 (Box-folder 3.70)